Nir Goldfriend

Tech-lead; Physicist; Problem-solver

☑ nircko@yahoo.com

J (+972) 52 - 6271527

in Nir Goldfriend

▼ Tel-Aviv ISR

A physicist in background and engineer in practice. More than 5 years experience in various research, system architecture and other engineering problems. Leading projects in optics, photonics, acoustics, signal and image processing, model-based reconstruction algorithms and machine-learning.

Work Experience

2021 – · · · ·

• Electro-optics system engineer Apple.

Physicist in camera and depth sensing architecture team.

Developing and optimizing electro-optic systems for camera and depth-sensing application. Collaborating with cross-functional teams, conducting in-depth analysis and handson testing, applying physics and engineering principles to develop high-performance optical components, interfacing with vendors for hardware integration, and leading problemsolving efforts to ensure system performance and user experience.

2019 – 2020

Academic Tutor The Hebrew University of Jerusalem.
 Physics Lab Instructor for Applied Physics and Electrical Engineering Department.

2014 - 2015

High school teacher and mentor Ramla-Lod High school.
I was a math teacher for at-risk students, implementing customized lesson plans tailored to meet the unique learning needs and challenges faced by their underserved backgrounds.

Education

2018 - 2021

MSc. Cum Lauda Applied Physics, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Israel.

I was a member at the Advanced Imaging Lab. I established a complex imaging modality combining optics, acoustics and computational image reconstruction, involving a bunch of elegant physics and computational skills. I also worked on remote sensing technique based on statistical optics and signal processing.

2015 - 2018

BSc. Physics and Chemistry, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Israel.

Program for outstanding students. During my bachelor I participated in "Etgar" honors program, worked on superconducting coplanar waveguide resonator used for quantum computing and developed a simulation of brain and neural activity of Mollusca (marine species)

Skills

Languages

Strong reading, writing and speaking competencies for English. Basic Mandarin-Chineese with several technical courses.

Coding and software development

• MATLAB, Python and basic bash; DevOps (CI/CD and infra); handson data science paradigms and tools...

Hardware development

 Symbolic and numerical simulations in optics and acoustics; Building system prototypes in various imaging and remote sensing setups.

Algorithms development

 Image processing and physical-based algorithm development for large-scale products.

Misc.

 Academic and industrial research, teaching, training, consultation, managing.

Publications, Patents, Press

- N. Goldfriend, Msc thesis: Compressive photo-acoustic 3d true optical resolution imaging, 2021.
- N. G. (Apple), "US Patent P64110US1 (*In review)," 2024.

Honors

- 2019 Dean's list, Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- 2018 HUJI NanoCenter Award for Excellence
- Scholarship for outstanding students, Hebrew University of Jerusalem.

Time-off

Volunteering

• Sunrise Association for young cancer patients

Good to talk

 Mongolia, Isla-de-Pascua, Mountaineering and Trekking Swimming and Cycling, Music play and theory, History and more